Financial data is noisy,
金融数据噪点很多
and sometimes the data we're working with is sparse.
有时候我们处理的数据很稀疏
For instance, it might have many missing values.
例如 可能缺少很多值
We can apply smoothing techniques across
我们可以对时间维度应用平滑技巧
the time dimension to help make the factor more robust to noise and sparse data.
使因子不容易受到噪点和稀疏数据的影响
Fundamental data is also sparse in nature,
基本面数据本身也很稀疏
since it is only updated in the US,
因为更新频率很低
for example, once every three months.
例如在美国 每隔三个月才更新一次
If we wish to use in a higher frequency,
如果我们想使用更新频率更高的数据
such as daily frequency,
例如每天更新
we should copy the most recent data over to
应该将最近的数据复制到每个新的一天
each new day until the next new data point arrives three months later.
直到三个月后出现下个新的数据点
We could also apply smoothing so that the daily data points
我们还可以应用平滑法
incorporate some weighted averaging of not only the most recent update,
使每日数据点以加权形式考虑最近的更新值
but also the value from previous quarters.
而且考虑前几个季度的值
To make our Alpha factor more robust to noise and sparse data,
为了使 Alpha 因子更不容易受噪点和稀疏数据的影响
we can apply a rolling window average.
我们可以应用滚动窗口平均法
A rolling window is a kind of smoothing technique.
滚动窗口是一种平滑技巧
A variation of a rolling window average is a weighted average,
滚动窗口平均的变体是加权平均
where the most recent Alpha may be given more weight
其中最近的 Alpha 权重更高
and prior Alpha values are included but given less weight.
之前的 Alpha 值也会考虑在内 但是权重更低
This is called linear decay.
这称为线性衰减
For example, if we choose a window length of two and took
例如 如果窗口长度设为 2
the weighted average of the most recent Alpha values and the prior days Alpha values,
并且计算最近 Alpha 值和之前的 Alpha 值的加权平均值
we could give the newest value a weight of two and the earlier value a weight of one.
那么可以将最新的值权重设为 2 之前的值权重设为 1
In general, for a window length of T,
通常 如果窗口长度为 T
we would give the most recent Alpha value a weight of
我们会将最新的 Alpha 值权重设为 T
T. Then for the earlier alpha values,
之前的 Alpha 值
we'd give them smaller weights.
权重更小
This technique can be very effective.
这种技巧很有效
In fact, I've seen several cases where the application of
实际上 我多次见到
a smoothing operator both increase the Sharpe ratio and decrease the turnover.
平滑法既提高了夏普比率 又降低了周转率
By the way, we'll cover the Sharpe ratio and
顺便提下 我们将在这节课的后面阶段
a proxy for measuring turnover later in this lesson.
讲解夏普比率以及衡量周转率的替代指标
These are both important evaluation metrics that help us find out if
这两个都是很重要的评估指标
an Alpha factor that we create has the potential to enhance a portfolio's performance.
有助于我们判断所创建的 Alpha 因子能否提高投资组合的业绩